sequencehome.co.uk 2016-10-16

# Privacy - Sequence

**Privacy Policy**  
This Privacy Policy explains how we use the personal information we collect about you, how you can instruct us if you prefer to limit the use of that information and the procedures that we have in place to safeguard your privacy.

In this Privacy Policy references to Sequence (UK) Limited shall mean Sequence (UK) Limited and those trading as Sequence including the trading names of Sequence (UK) Limited and its subsidiaries and subsidiary undertakings from time to time (as those expressions are defined in sections 736 and 258 respectively of the Companies Act 1985 (as amended). In this Privacy Policy, the expressions "we", "us" or "our" means Sequence (UK) Limited and its subsidiaries and subsidiary undertakings from time to time.

Sequence (UK) Limited is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected in accordance with the law, and all personal information shall be held and used in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. Further details of which are available from the Information Commissioner’s website www.ico.gov.uk .

Sequence (UK) Limited is registered as Data Controller of your Information, Registration Number Z8920800.

**1\. The information we collect and how we use it**  
1.1 When you enquire or register for products and services provided by Sequence (UK) Limited you will provide us with certain personal information. This information may be provided online through our websites, by telephone, by electronic communications or via direct contact with our employees. This information will be stored on our computer systems and in our manual records.

1.2 The information that you provide will allow us to process your registration, confirm your identity and communicate with you to provide relevant products and services to suit your needs. The relevant information is then used by us, our agents and sub-contractors to communicate with you on any matter relating to your relationship with Sequence (UK) Ltd in general. Your information may also be transferred or forwarded to other members of Sequence (UK) Limited or its group for administration, marketing or information gathering and similar purposes. Any calls that you make to our customer teams may be recorded for the purposes of our business management, training and security.

1.3 We may, during the course of your relationship with us, request additional information relevant to the provision of specific services; this could include details such as previous property ownership and financial details for mortgage purposes. This information may be shared with third parties where they are involved in the delivery of products or services. In such instances all information provided to the third party will be subject to the terms of this privacy policy and those of the relevant third party privacy policy, details of which will be made available by inclusion in any initial correspondence / documentation that is provided.

1.4 Some of the services provided by Sequence (UK) Limited may be supplied by third parties and therefore we will pass on to the relevant party the information it requires in order to fulfil your needs. In order that we are able to monitor supplier performance and customer satisfaction these third parties will pass certain information such as fulfilment and complaints data back to us. Your information will be handled in accordance with the relevant data protection legislation at all times.

1.5 We will use your contact details to keep you informed about suitable products and services provided by Sequence (UK) Limited and carefully selected third parties. This may involve sharing some or all of your information with carefully selected third parties.

1.6 Where information is to be shared with carefully selected third parties, Sequence (UK) Limited will endeavour to provide you with a further opportunity to opt out of receiving details of individual products and services at the relevant time.

1.7 If you would prefer not to receive information from Sequence (UK) Limited or carefully selected third parties you can opt out by contacting the branch, writing to the Data Protection Office at our registered address or by emailing unsubscribe@sequencehome.co.uk .

1.8 From time to time we may provide your information to our customer service agencies for research, survey and analysis purposes so that we can monitor and improve the services we provide. We or our agents and sub- contractors may occasionally contact you including by post, email or telephone to ask you for your feedback and comments on our services.

**2\. How we protect your information**  
2.1 In line with the requirements of the Data Protection Act 1998 we follow strict security procedures to ensure that personal information is not damaged, destroyed or disclosed to a third party without your permission and to prevent unauthorised access to your information. The Information that we collect is stored in a secure facility with restricted physical access. We also use a number of security measures to prevent electronic access. Where information is shared with third parties in line with this policy similar security measures are used to protect your information.

2.2 The access to and use of the information that we collect is restricted to our employees who need the information to perform a specific job role or activity. Where information is shared with third parties in line with this policy similar security measures are used to protect your information.

2.3 Your information will be held and processed on computers within the UK and will not be transferred outside of the European Economic Area.

2.4 We will retain your information for a reasonable period or for as long as is required by law.

2.5 The Internet is not a secure medium and as such you acknowledge and agree that Sequence (UK) Limited shall not, to the fullest extent permitted by law, be liable to you for any unauthorised usage, interception, distribution, damage or destruction of personal data.

2.6 When communicating with Sequence (UK) Ltd by email you should ensure that you take all reasonable precautions to protect any sensitive personal data. When you register to use Sequencehome.co.uk you will be asked to create a password, it is your responsibility to choose a secure password. You must keep this password confidential and must not disclose it to or share it with anyone. You will be responsible for all activities that occur under your password and If you know or suspect that someone else knows your password you should notify us immediately.

**3.0 Additional terms covering websites operated by Sequence (UK) Ltd**  
3.1 Certain parts of the Site can be used without registration, if you are not a registered user of the Site and only visit the Site then the activities and terms outlined in clauses 3.3 and 3.9 are applicable to your usage of the site. Some services will require you to register with the Site and when you register to use the Site we need to know your name, address and other contact details.

3.2 For your convenience we will store your registration information so that you do not have to complete all the sections of enquiry forms each time you use the Site. You can update your information at any time by accessing the MyAccount menu item on the main navigation bar.

3.3 The services provided through the Site may be supplied by third parties and therefore we will pass on to the relevant party the information it requires in order to fulfil your needs. In order that we are able to monitor usage of the Site, supplier performance and customer satisfaction these third parties will pass certain information such as fulfilment and complaints data back to us. In addition, third parties who provide content or functionality through the Site or via links from the Site may require information to be collected on the Site or via links from the Site or may pass such information back to us. In such instances all information received will be subject to the terms of the relevant third party privacy policy (in cases where they receive information) or this Privacy Policy (in instances where we receive information) and at all times handled in accordance with the relevant data protection legislation.

3.4 Where you have provided consent we may use your information to contact you about related goods and services that may be of interest to you, this may involve sharing some or all of your information with carefully selected third parties.

3.5 On occasion we carry out surveys or other promotional activities which may be for our own benefit or for more general interest. Participation in any survey is entirely optional.

3.6 We may also wish to provide you with information about special features of our Site or any special service or products which we think may be of interest to you.

3.7 Sequence would also like to keep you informed (by telephone, post or e-mail) of selected products and services available from us and our carefully chosen suppliers. If you would prefer not to receive this information you can update your communication preferences at any time via the MyAccount item on the main navigation bar. Alternatively please let us know by either sending an e-mail message to websitefeedback@sequencehome.co.uk or by writing to us at our registered address.

3.9 Our use of Cookies

3.9.1 A cookie is a small piece of information that a site puts on your hard disk or stores in your computer's memory so that it can remember something about you at a later time. It is a mechanism that allows the server to store its own information about a user on the user's own computer. This is because each request for a web page is independent of all other requests, so the web page server has no memory of what pages it has shown you or anything about your previous visits. A cookie records your preferences when using a particular site, ensuring that you are not shown the same information and/or are only shown information you have stated that you are interested in. In order to use the Site you agree to let cookies be saved as they are an important part of navigation of the Site.

3.9.2 We or our third party advertisers may also use cookies to monitor the effectiveness of advertising on the Site.

3.9.3 Cookies used by this site. 

A cookie is used to store your preferences for viewing search results and may contain a unique identifier so that our servers can temporarily record what search terms you used.  
We also use the cookie to allow you to log into the MyAccount part of the site, this will store some personal information (First Name, Last Name, Email Address, Home Phone Number) that may be used should you need to fill out an enquiry form. This information is removed when you log out of MyAccount or when your session expires.

3.9.4 Third party cookies used on the site.

Google Analytics a service that generates detailed statistics about our website visitors. Their cookies typically store anonymous information such as whether a visitor has been to the site before, the time of the current visit and what was the referrer site the visitor came from.

AddThis a social bookmarking service, allowing visitors to bookmark an item using a variety of social networks such as Facebook and Twitter. They have a comprehensive privacy document at http://www.addthis.com/privacy. They use cookies to store a unique identifier that may be used to collect information about you for online behavioural advertising. You can easily stop AddThis from collecting any information about you for online behavioural advertising by opting out at http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out. This will prevent advertisers from receiving any data that could be used to tailor advertising for you. This will also prevent websites that use AddThis from learning about your interests in order to personalize their content or services for you.

3.10 Please ensure you keep your password confidential and remember to log out by closing down the browser windows when not using the Site to prevent unauthorised access.

3.11 Updating your details - If any of the information that you have provided to sequencehome.co.uk changes, for example if you change your e-mail address or name please update your profile at any time via the MyAccount item on the main navigation bar. If you experience any issues please send an e-mail message to website.feedback@sequencehome.co.uk.

**4\. Your consent**  
4.1 BY SUBMITTING YOUR INFORMATION YOU GIVE YOUR UNCONDITIONAL CONSENT TO THE USE OF THAT INFORMATION AS SET OUT IN THIS POLICY. If we change our Privacy Policy we will post the changes on this page, and may place notices on other pages of the Site, so that you may be aware of the information we collect and how we use it. We will also e-mail you should we make any significant changes so that you may consent to our use of your information in that way. Continued use of the service will signify that you agree to any such changes.

4.2 Where in any case you provide information about individuals other than yourself you warrant that you have obtained that person's consent to the use of such information.

**5\. How to contact Sequence (UK) Limited**  
5.1 We welcome your views about the Site and our Privacy Policy. If you would like to contact us with any enquiries or comments please send an e-mail to [website.feedback@sequencehome.co.uk](mailto:website.feedback@sequencehome.co.uk)

5.2 If you wish to make a data subject access request (a request for access to your personal data) under the Data Protection Act 1998, please write to the Sequence (UK) Ltd at Group Legal Services, Bridgegate House, 5 Bridge Place, Lower Bridge Street, Chester CH1 1SA or email to [julian.kelbrick@sequencehome.co.uk](mailto:julian.kelbrick@sequencehome.co.uk) or to [faye.davies@sequencehome.co.uk](mailto:faye.davies@sequencehome.co.uk) and we shall acknowledge your request and confirm what we will need from you to carry out your request.
